Menu [](https://ccm.net/) 

Search  

*   [Language](javascript:void(0);)

[](javascript:void(0)) [](http://www.twitter.com/CCMnet) [  ](https://www.facebook.com/CCM.US) [](https://www.pinterest.fr/ccmneteng/) 

Search   

1.  [Accueil](https://ccm.net/)
2.  [Internet Archaeology](https://ccm.net/contents/)
3.  [CCM](https://ccm.net/contents/ccm-8)
4.  [Terms of Use](https://ccm.net/contents/terms-of-use-4284272066)

Processing of Personal Data - CCM
=================================

Latest update on **Tuesday 7 January 2020 à 09:42** by noctambule28.

**CCM BENCHMARK GROUP** is responsible for the collection and the processing of personal data.  
  
**CCM BENCHMARK GROUP** is an _SAS_ (Simplified Joint-Stock Company) with a capital of 1 848 864,45 €. Headquartered at:  94 rue de Provence – 75009 Paris, France   
Registered in the Registre du Commerce et des Sociétés (Registry of Commerce and Companies) as number 512 085 630 PARIS  

*   [Your choices and rights of opposition and deletion of cookies on our sites](#your-choices-and-rights-of-opposition-and-deletion-of-cookies-on-our-sites)

Nature of collected data
------------------------

In respect of the privacy of its users, CCM BENCHMARK GROUP promises that the collection and the processing of personal information carried out within this site are done in accordance with the law.  
  
The information that we collect originates from:  
  
Either the voluntary registration of an email address which permits you to receive one of our newsletters or offers from our partners;  
The input of your personal data while registering to one of our sites;  
Or the data issued from your visit to our site via cookies: viewing a web page, clicking a link, a search.  

What do we do with this information?
------------------------------------

### Purpose of collected data

Depending on the case, the uses include:  
If you are subscribed to one of our newsletters: in this case, your email address is used for the sending of our email campaigns and internal announcements;  
If you agree to receive email offers from one of our site partners during your registration, we may use the data collected to send you advertising campaigns of our partners according to your navigation behavior on our site. In no case will this data be transmitted to third parties without your prior consent;  
If you are registered on one of our sites, your data is used for the management of your account (customer service searches, technical difficulties);  
The internet sites of CCM Benchmark Group collect personal data through the use of cookies (see the complete presentation below in paragraph 3) for the purposes of targeted advertising.  
Furthermore, the personal data is stored.  

### Your rights concerning your personal data

You have a right to access, modify, oppose, and delete your personal data.  
You may exercise these rights at any moment, and by any means, notably:  
By postal mail at the following address:  
  
**CCM BENCHMARK GROUP**   
"Personal Data - CCM"  
94 rue de Provence – 75009 Paris, France   
  
By email at the following address: contact \[at\] commentcamarche.net  
The request must be accompanied by a photocopy of a valid ID card.  
Your request will be processed within a maximum delay of 2 months following receipt.  
We remind you that abusive claims are punishable by law.  
In some cases, you may also exercise these rights directly:  
If you are subscribed to one of our newsletters: You may at any moment unsubscribe by clicking the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of every email;  
If you accept to receive offers from our partners: You may at any moment unsubscribe by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of every email;  
If you have voluntarily subscribed to one of our sites: You may at any moment access, modify, or delete your data while connected to the Member Space;  
In regards to cookies, the means of direct opposition are specified below in paragraph 3-3.  

Cookie Policy
-------------

### About Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that websites send to a user’s terminal (computer, tablet, cell phone, or any other device optimized for internet use) when you consult a web page or online publication. It allows websites to personalize themselves according to your profile, which contains collected data such as (depending on the case) your name, your email address, the time and date of connection, the operating system of your computer, frequented sites…  

### Purpose of Cookies

Four types of cookies, each explained below, may therefore be saved to your device during a visit to our websites:  

#### Technical Cookies

Technical Cookies are necessary for the navigation of our website, and allow access to different products and services. Technical Cookies allow us to recognize you, to signal your visit to a particular page, and to improve your browsing experience: to adapt the site’s presentation to your terminal’s display preferences (language, display resolution), and to memorize passwords and other information relative to a form that you filled out on the site (registration or access to the Member Space). Technical Cookies also permit us to implement safety measures (for example, when you are asked to login to the Member Space again after a certain amount of time). We remind you that the deletion of Technical Cookies may impair your access to the site and/or to the services offered.  

#### Analytical Cookies

Analytical Cookies are issued by our technical service providers in order to measure the audience of different content sections of our site so that we may evaluate and better organize them. These cookies also allow, if necessary, to detect navigation problems, and therefore to improve the usability of services. These cookies only produce anonymous statistics and traffic volumes, and exclude all individual information.  

#### Advertising Cookies

Advertising Cookies are issued by our partners in the advertising spaces of our sites. The exploitation of these spaces contributes to the financing of content and services that we place at your disposition. These cookies are deposited by our partners as part of our advertising partnership under which the company may collect data about the content consulted on our site. First and foremost, these cookies permit to count the total number of advertisements seen on our public sites, to identify these advertisements, and to count the number of users who click on each advertisement. If necessary, these cookies also allow us to follow subsequent actions performed by users on these pages to which these advertisements lead in order to calculate the sum due to the advertising broadcast channel (communication agency, advertising agency, site/broadcast medium), and to compile statistics.  
  
These Advertising Cookies also permit us to adapt advertising content displayed on your terminal in our advertising spaces, according to your navigation on our site and, as appropriate, depending on location data (longitude and latitude) transmitted by your terminal with your prior consent. These cookies may ultimately allow us to tailor advertising content displayed on your terminal in our advertising space based on the personal data that you have voluntarily provided (targeted advertising).  

#### Social Media Cookies

Social Media Cookies permit us to share content of our sites with other people, or to inform others of your inquiry or your opinion concerning content on one of our sites. This is notably in the case of the « Share », and « Like » buttons on Facebook or Twitter.  
  
The social network application is provided with a switch with which it is likely to identify you, even if you may not have used it when viewing our site. This type of application button may allow the social network to follow your navigation to our site, just because the social network is active on your terminal (open session) during your visit to our site. We do not have any control over this process used by social networks to collect information about your browsing on our site and to associate this information with other personal data that they may have.  
  
We invite you to review the privacy policies of these social networks in order to familiarize yourself with the use of these cookies, including any advertising and navigation information that they may gather through these application switches.  
  
These protection policies allow you to exercise your rights over these social networks, particularly in configuring your accounts to use each of these social networks.  

Your choices and rights of opposition and deletion of cookies on our sites
--------------------------------------------------------------------------

In using our site, you agree to the use of the aforementioned cookies. However, you may at any time choose to deactivate them in your browser. Your browser may also be configured to signal you systematically when cookies are deposited into your device, and ask you to accept them or not.  
  
If your device is used by several people and/or uses multiple browsers, we cannot ensure with certainty that services and advertisements will correspond to your use of this terminal and not those of another user.  
  
In this case, the sharing of your computer and your browser settings with others are your responsibility and your choice.  

### Refusing or deleting a cookie through your navigation system

If you use Internet Explorer: click on the “Tools” button, followed by “Internet Options”. Under the “History” tab, click on “Select”. Select the “Cookies” check box, and then click “Delete”. [https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/delete-and-manage-cookies-168dab11-0753-043d-7c16-ede5947fc64d#ie=ie-11](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/delete-and-manage-cookies-168dab11-0753-043d-7c16-ede5947fc64d#ie=ie-11)  
  
If you use Firefox: click on the “Menu” button and choose “Preferences”. Select the “Privacy” tab and go to the “History” section to set your cookie preferences.  
[https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/disable-third-party-cookies](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/disable-third-party-cookies)  
  
If you use Safari: Click on “Preferences” > “Privacy” and then “View Cookies”. Select the cookies that you would like to deactivate and click on “Delete” or “Delete All”.  
https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?viewlocale=en\_US&locale=en\_US  
  
If you use Chrome: click on the menu icon, followed by “Parameters”. At the bottom of the page, click on “View advanced options”. In the “Confidentiality” section, click on “Content Parameters”.  
To deactivate cookies, select “Block sites from setting any data”  
To delete a specific cookie, click on “Cookies and site data”, and use the mouse to hover over the site that issued the cookie. Click on the “X” that appears on the right corner, or click “Delete All”.  

### Refusing an Advertising Cookie

You may manage the use and exploitation of cookies by visiting the Advertising Cookies management platform proposed by advertising professionals: [https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) and by following the instructions given. The companies listed on this platform offer you the possibility to refuse or accept cookies used by them to adapt advertisements according to your browsing information.  
  
Note that proceeding with this deactivation prevents the display of all interest-based ads, but you will continue to receive other advertisements that are not targeted.  

### Refusing a cookie issued by a social network

If you would like to read more about cookies on our sites’ social networks, we invite you to consult the documentation on the sites of our social editors:  
Google+: [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en)  
Twitter: [https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/twitter-do-not-track](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/twitter-do-not-track)  
LinkedIn: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy)  
Yahoo: [https://www.verizonmedia.com/policies/us/en/verizonmedia/privacy/topics/cookies/index.html](https://www.verizonmedia.com/policies/us/en/verizonmedia/privacy/topics/cookies/index.html)  
YouTube: [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en)  
Facebook: [https://www.facebook.com/](https://www.facebook.com/)  
[https://magazinedelledonne.it/faq/11384-coma-cause-sintomi-e-trattamento](https://magazinedelledonne.it/faq/11384-coma-cause-sintomi-e-trattamento)  

Share[](https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fccm.net%2Fcontents%2F957-processing-of-personal-data-ccm "Share")[](http://pinterest.com/pin/create/link/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fccm.net%2Fcontents%2F957-processing-of-personal-data-ccm&description=Share&media=https%3A%2F%2Fimg-16.ccm2.net%2FIRsMmwaZ_aTUhdyOWg0NGjAHyMs%3D%2F200x%2F9ea67803bd094fea821e50cc064ca727%2Fccm-encyclopedia%2FkfSgNHLL-ccm-rouge.png "Share")

CCM is a leading international tech website. Our content is written in collaboration with [IT experts](https://ccm.net/contents/938-ccm-who-we-are), under the direction of Jean-François Pillou, founder of CCM.net. CCM reaches more than 50 million unique visitors per month and is available in 11 languages.

Related

*   Privacy Policy
*   [Twitter, Facebook, and Google Face Privacy Policy Lawsuit](https://ccm.net/news/24736-twitter-facebook-and-google-face-privacy-policy-lawsuit) \- News
*   [Your account was disabled because we determined that you are ineligible to use facebook. for more information about our policies](https://ccm.net/forum/affich-1031835-facebook-disabled-ineligible#answers) ✓ \- [Forum - Facebook](https://ccm.net/forum/facebook-149/solved)
*   [Flipkart return policy](https://ccm.net/faq/57201-how-to-return-exchange-a-product-and-get-refund-on-flipkart) \- [How-To - Internet](https://ccm.net/faq/internet-156)
*   [Google account disabled due to policy violation](https://ccm.net/forum/affich-888906-gmail-account-has-been-disabled#answers) ✓ \- [Forum - Gmail](https://ccm.net/forum/gmail-146/solved)
*   [Privacy and app encryption vivo forgot](https://ccm.net/forum/affich-1077708-forgotten-file-safe-and-privacy-app-encryption-password-in-vivo-v5s#answers) \- [Forum - System software](https://ccm.net/forum/system-software-179)

This document, titled « Processing of Personal Data - CCM », is available under the [Creative Commons](https://ccm.net/contents/955-copyright-information) license. Any copy, reuse, or modification of the content should be sufficiently credited to [CCM](https://ccm.net/contents/ccm.net) ([ccm.net](https://ccm.net/contents/ccm.net)).

[Previous

Legal

](https://ccm.net/contents/956-terms-of-use-for-ccm-net-legal-matters " Legal")

[Next

Terms and Conditions

](https://ccm.net/contents/953-general-terms-and-conditions-of-use "Terms and Conditions")

### Subscribe To Our Newsletter!

Subscribe To Our Newsletter!

The information gathered is for Communitic International to ensure the sending of the newsletter.

The information will be used subject to terms and conditions, for advertising purposes.

You reserve the right to access and change your personal data, aswell as the right to request its deletion within the limits permitted by law.

You can also review your targeting options. For more information, click this [privacy policy](https://ccm.net/contents/957-processing-of-personal-data-ccm) .

Recommended

DON'T MISS
